Claude has evolved with today's
generation of Claude 5 models being a
lot more powerful than everything that
came before. But the way most people set
up their agents and their operating
systems have not caught up. So today
I'll teach you this different framework
of setting up your Aentic OS so you can
get the full power from these new models
to make your [music] systems faster,
have your setup cost less, and
ultimately be more productive than you
ever thought possible. I'll also break
this down in four simple parts so that
by the end of it, you'll be using agents
[music] better than 99% of people. And
if you're new, my name is Jay. I spent
over a decade working with brands you
may know, have been in AI since my
masters in data science. Now I'm running
an AI business and one of the largest AI
communities globally. Let's dive into
it.
So this is my Agentic OS or more
specifically the virtual command center
for my Agentic operating system. And
from this one view, I can access summary
information for the applications that I
use daily, like events in my calendar
and time zones that I care about. A
quick summary of my emails, including
the messages that Claude is flagging as
needing my attention. There's also quick
links here to some of the micro
applications that I created myself and I
use on the daily, which I'll talk more
about in a bit. And I also have custom
widgets here, like this one for YouTube,
because obviously I do a lot of content.
And here I also have a view of my
routines and scheduled tasks and which
ones are going to fire on what time. And
for some specific skills where it makes
sense to trigger them from this
dashboard, I also have this skills deck
where I can adjust the effort level as
well as the model to be used for this
specific run and also run it straight
from this dashboard. And because these
are widgets and Cloud Code is actually
really good in creating these for me,
you can freely adjust the size as well
as the placement of these widgets and
even create new ones depending on what
you need. And lastly, because of the way
that I use Cloud Code where I just
consistently ask it to create artifacts
for me, I just had it make me this
artifacts ring where I can just easily
find the assets and artifacts that it
made for me in the past. So, for
example, if I'm looking for artifacts
for a client called THRO, then I can
just search for that and I'm able to
also open this specific HTML file that
it created for me back in the 5th of
August. And lastly, and very importantly
here in the center, if I click on that,
that will just give me access to my own
second brain system, which is important
at least in the work that I do because
it's crucial for me to visualize these
systems so that I can explain them
better and so that I can visually show
the skills and other files in my
workspace, which is important in my
work. Now, I'll show more of that second
brain in a bit, but really this whole
Aentic OS dashboard, it's great,
especially if you're a visually
motivated person like myself. And this
also works well if you're serving
clients and if you're into AI consulting
because creating something like this for
a client is also a service that you can
package and sell. To give a quick
example, this one's a design mockup for
a financial services firm here in
Australia. Here's another one for a
company called Beto Green. And the point
being is that if you have the
foundations in place for your own
personal agentic OS, then with today's
really powerful AI models, then it's
really quite easy to customize it to
whichever client that you are serving.
And by the way, if you want to learn how
to build and sell AI systems that
businesses actually pay for, then that's
pretty much all we do over at the
Robbernuggets community, where not only
do you get access to the Claw Living
Master Class, which we update every week
and takes you from zero to mastery with
the latest on AI, but you also get
access to our agents as a service
course, which walks you through how to
actually get paid for all these AI
skills that you are learning. You also
get to be part of a genuinely great
community of AI builders. In fact, you
can see just some of the recent wins our
members are getting from the program
right here. So if you want to start
earning from AI then check that just in
the pin comment below. Now back to the
video. Now having a dashboard like this
is great. It's visually appealing and
you get to see all aspects of your work
and your business which is pretty much
why I use it as my homepage now on the
daily. But I'd say this visual interface
captures only around 20 to 30% of the
value of this agentic operating system
because the remaining 70% of the value
really lies on what's underneath.
Because a big part of this operating
system is how you've organized your
context and your workspace so that your
system and your AI agent in this case
cloud code works for you and not against
you. And there's many ways to organize
your own operating system, but at least
how I think of it personally and how I
teach it in our community is via what I
call the ARMS framework. It's very
simple to remember because it's sort of
like giving Claude, which is your AI
agent employee, its own arms, its own
workspace. And the core idea here is if
you figure out how to best set up these
four aspects of your OS, then you'll be
way ahead of 99% of other agentic AI
users. And those four elements of the
ARMS framework would be your
applications that you use, the routines
or scheduled tasks that you run, your
memory system, as well as the skills
that you have your agent use. And in my
view, the best way to learn this is
actually from bottom up. So for most
users of these agentic AI systems, first
you learn about skills and then you set
up your own memory system. Then once
you're confident there, that's only when
you rise up and you can actually
schedule your own routines or even
create your own applications or create
connectors for the applications that
you're using. And so what I'll do for
the rest of this lesson is I'll just go
through this from bottom up. And for
each of them, I'm going to share three
levels of how you can use them so that
you can just freely skip ahead to the
ones that you don't know yet, but give
it the depth of what I plan to cover in
this video. For sure, you'll pick up a
few nuggets along the way that you
probably haven't known yet. And by the
end of it, if you watch the whole thing,
then you'll be able to level up your own
agentic skills to the point that you can
also build out an agentic OS similar to
what I have here, but customized for
your setup. And also, just to make it
easy for you, I've also published this
nine-page PDF guide where if you read
through that or just send it to your
cloud code, then your agent will be able
to guide you on how to set up this
operating system as well. So, you can
just grab that in the description below.
So, now let's start with the first
element, which is skills. Now, you most
likely have encountered skills before
because they're basically just shortcuts
to your SOPs, to your standard operating
procedures. And the basic principle here
is when you find yourself prompting
Claude for the same task twice, then
it's probably good to make it into a
skill. Now, in the very first level, if
you're just getting started, it's more
than likely that the first skills that
you access are the ones that are
pre-built by Entropic. And the way you
would have access those is the Cloud
Desktop app under customize. You'll have
a section here for skills where you can
browse the ones that Entropic gives to
you. But from here you can see that one
of the more popular skills from Entropic
is this skill creator skill. And the
reason why that is is that generally I
do advise people to create their own
skills as well because each of our work
is really custom to us. And so when you
get to the habit of creating your own
skills, the faster that you can get more
refined and better results from Claude
and you can find inspirations for skills
that you can create everywhere. For
example, a few days ago, I found this
post on X which looks to be a really
good tip just to make your computer run
a bit faster. And so what I did a few
days ago is to just paste that whole
tweet and then just invoke the skill
creator skill. And if you send this,
that will just let Cloud Code create
that skill for you so that you can test
it out. Which, by the way, at least for
my workspace, this has been quite
effective. So if you've been having
trouble with Cloud Code or even Codeex
clogging up your systems and making it
slower, then this might be something
that you want to try out as well. Now,
once you've created or tested out a few
skills yourself, then you start to
realize that there's a second level to
this. Because contrary to what some
people might believe, a skill file is
actually not just the markdown file.
Because some of the most powerful skills
that you can add to your arsenal
actually have rich references that they
can pull from. And just to make that a
bit clearer with an example, if I go
ahead and find that cleanup skill that
we made earlier, this one's a pretty
thin and light skill because it only has
this one skill.md as you can see. And if
we go ahead and open that, really a
skill.md is just a markdown text file.
And this just provides instructions to
your cloud code on how to execute this
specific command. But let's say if I
find a more complex skill like this one
for Robo. Then you can see that this
skill that I invoke with /robo actually
has multiple files connected to it. And
if I just open the folder of that so you
can see better. Then you can see in this
folder that there is this skill file
which is the markdown file that gives
instructions to claude code on how to
use this skill. And if we go back here
we can find that as well. And from this
skill.mmd, you can see that it's
essentially functioning as a router to
these other reference files that are
also from within that /robo skill
folder. And the reason why that's
important for this skill specifically is
because this is actually the design
system that I've been using for a lot of
our videos and a lot of our company
assets. And so if I open this brand
HTML, you can see this provides us some
guidance on the robo style. So it has
guidance on the fonts, it has guidance
on the color palettes. And so having
visual references for your skills like
this works really well, especially for
skills that are meant for design. And so
for some cases where you want the skill
to do more complex tasks, what you can
actually do is to enrich it and not be
limited to just one skill.md to house
all of your skills as files. So for
example, this PDF guide that I was
talking about, the reason why this is
welldesigned and already knows our brand
is because the way that I actually
create this is using that really
good/robo skill. So to make something
like this, what I do is just give a
simple prompt like make a PDF guide with
/robo on how to set up an agentic OS.
And then I just answer a few questions
that Claude has so that it is aligned
with my intention. And because that
/robo skill is already so well defined
with a lot of visual artifacts and
references, I actually get a
well-designed PDF guide like this in
just one or two prompts. And if you need
a quick starter prompt just to let
Claude find your thick skills and
actually make them into ones with richer
references instead of stuffing
everything into the skill.md, then you
can use this prompt. Just screenshot it
to kickstart that process. And when you
have those, now you can get to level
three, which in some instances is
actually useful to trigger skills even
outside of your chat sessions. To give
one use case, that cleanup skill that I
created before, I actually added it to
this skills deck so that I can trigger
it from this page instead of having to
open up cloud code in another terminal
or chat session and typing out slash
cleanup there because most of the time I
actually run this skill whenever I see
my device slowing down. And so when
that's done, what it essentially does is
also provide an output or a report
similar to this one where if I open
that, it just provides me with this
summary of the results of that skills
run. And the way that you run any of
your skills headlessly, meaning without
having to open up a chat session, is
through this Claude feature called
Claude P. And without getting too
technical, what that essentially does is
spin up a quick session where it sends a
oneshot prompt to Claude using the model
and effort level that you want. And you
can see for this specific example, the
only thing that was sent to Claude is
this /cleup command. And so this becomes
useful when you want to integrate your
skills into dashboards like these or
even as part of internal applications,
let's say that you want to create for
your team or your company. And like with
most of the stuff that I'll teach you
today, the great thing about the tools
that we're using now like Cloud Code or
Codeex is that you actually don't need
to learn how to use any extra technical
tooling in order to make this happen. As
long as you're aware of this feature
like cloud hyphen P, then what you can
do is copy a prompt like this, which you
can just screenshot and send to your
cloud code. And that can get you started
with integrating any of your skills into
your own operating system. Now, let's go
to the next layer, which is memory. And
it's important because the more that you
use cloud code, the more context or
files you have that you create. And at
the very first level, what you have
really is a workspace with a bunch of
files. So, for example, for my case, the
folder in my computer that I set as my
Agentic operating system or workspace is
this folder called Robo. And you can see
there's a lot of files and folders
already in here. Now, when you're just
getting started and you only have a few
files, it'll mostly be okay for you
experience-wise. But the problem starts
to arise when your context and your
files build up so much that it's
actually making it harder for your agent
to find things. So, for example, for my
case personally, when I built out this
second brain system and I pointed it to
that robo folder, it's only then that I
found out that I actually have something
like 60,000 files already in that
folder. And so, you can imagine it's
probably difficult for the agent to
navigate through that, which would have
a direct impact on number one, how fast
you can retrieve information from your
workspace, and number two, how quickly
you run out of your usage in your plan.
And so as soon as you start to see some
slow down your systems in retrieving
memory, I advise people to move to level
two, which essentially is just
organizing that workspace that is
optimized for an agent. And I say
optimize for an agent because if you
remember if you're a millennial or a Gen
X when Windows or Mac operating systems
first came to be, you probably had a
period in your life when you wanted to
organize things neatly into folders and
to properly rename the files and folders
so that you as the person can easily
navigate through that workspace and
actually find the things that you need.
In this new paradigm where your agents
are the ones operating on your files,
you don't really need to pay as much
attention to the names and the
navigability of your files from within
this more traditional file explorer
view. Because with these agentic
operating systems, at the minimum, what
you should have in your workspace are
what I like to call as a router files.
And that's best illustrated here in this
second brain system where the center of
it is your claw.md. And that by itself
is a router. And in my cloud.md that
just provides cloud context on the
different departments that I work with
so that when I work on content it knows
that it just operates within this set of
files. When I work on my community let's
say it knows that these files are the
ones that are relevant and so on and so
forth. And then for each of these
departments I also have a dedicated
router file. So for example if I search
for the content.md file in here but
you'll see inside that markdown file is
just a list of skills as well as
reference files. so that when I'm
looking for something content related,
it'll be able to look at this list and
immediately navigate through my files
and find the stuff that I want. And so
instead of focusing on organizing your
workspace in terms of folders and files,
which is probably second nature for a
lot of us who grew up with this older,
more traditional operating systems like
Windows or Mac. But remember, since
these agents like Claude Code can parse
through files at lightning speed, it's
always much better to just give them
these router files so that your agent
can find what you need in the fastest
way possible with the least amount of
steps. And again, like I mentioned, you
can start this setup through just by
talking to your agent. What you can do
is just copy this prompt and give it to
your cloud code and it'll get you
started with setting up those router
files. And then once you're ready to
upgrade your memory system, then you can
move on to level three, which is having
your visual second brain system, which
is the one that I was showing you
earlier. And the reason why this is
important for a lot of people is that it
allows you to see how all of your files
and folders connect. And also, it allows
you to search for things faster. And
you've already seen me do this through
this video when I'm showing my skills or
how my claw.md connects to different
departments or how these different files
connect. That's actually really valuable
for a lot of people who are more visual
and can understand things better when
you show it to them in this format
versus having to take them through again
that traditional file explorer view
which is not really the most engaging
format. The other thing is if let's say
you want to go and search for the
cleanup skill in here usually with file
explorer it is much longer to find but
earlier as I illustrated if I look for
that cleanup skill from my OS or my
second brain system then I can
immediately find that and I can
immediately show it and preview it. Now,
let's go and talk about routines. And to
me, this is the third layer because once
you've mastered skills and memory,
that's only really when you get the
confidence to actually let your agent do
tasks even without you monitoring it.
And that's the essence of routines
because routines are essentially just
scheduled tasks. And in the first level,
the way that you do this is really
simple because it comes out of the box
with cloud code. And in the cloud
desktop app, if you head to routines
here on the left sidebar, you'll be able
to draft routines in here just by
talking to Claude in natural language.
And you can see I have a couple here.
The one that I use a lot is this YouTube
to substack daily and which if you open
that, you can see exactly when that
repeats, which for this one is every day
at 8:00 a.m. And in a nutshell, a
routine is just a prompt that Claude
sends to itself at that given time that
you set. So for this specific routine,
what it does is it just turns any new
video that we have on the channel and it
drafts that into a newsletter post and
my tone of voice. And when that runs in
the background, that also puts the
artifact here in my Aentic OS. So let's
say this previous video that I had
called six new rules of cloud code. When
it's time for me to review that, I just
open it and it provides me with several
options and drafts that I can just
iterate and review. And because this
uses a custom skill as well for that
routine, then I already have something
like 70% 80% confidence that this is
within my tone of voice and I only need
to apply some minor edits to it for it
to get to production. But if you notice
here, here in my routines, I only have a
few in my Cloud Code desktop app. And
the reason why that is is because at
level one, even though they're really
simple to set up, the key limitation
with these local routines is that they
only run while your computer is on. And
so a lot of my routines are actually in
level two where I have those scheduled
tasks running in the cloud so that even
if my computer is off, I have the
assurance that those scheduled tasks
will run even without me. And there's
many solutions to this now. OpenClaw
probably popularized it before. Grockbot
is also pretty new, although it's
paywalled to a pretty high price point
at the moment. So the one that I
personally have set up and use is
Hermes. And I have several other
tutorials on Hermes on this channel. Or
if you're part of the community, you can
also just go through this Hermes agent
masterass to use it in the best way
possible. But in a nutshell, the reason
why Hermes is so powerful is because it
is 24/7. It's always on. And the reason
why it's 24/7 and always on is because
for most people who are using Hermes,
they give it its own computer. Like for
myself, I give it a computer in the
cloud. And so that's why if you look at
my routines firing board in here, most
of the scheduled tasks that I have
personally are already loaded in my
Hermes agent. But a key aspect of this
that most people miss is that if your
Hermes agent has its own computer, then
how can it access all of the skills and
all of the context that you have built
up with cloud code? And there's many
ways to do this. But for me personally,
and I think for a lot of people who are
just getting started with this, what you
can use is a tool called Sync Thing. And
sync thing is a really good and free
open- source software that basically
what it does is literally just sync
things between your computers. And so if
you point it to your workspace that
cloud code works on and also install it
in the computer that your Hermes agent
uses, then you'll be able to sync the
files that you want, including all the
skills and memory files that you want to
share with Hermes. And as usual, all you
need to get started is just one single
prompt, and you can use this one if
you're interested to try it out. Now,
when it comes to the next stage of
routines, this is actually something
that I think is coming soon by default
for cloud. And I actually know some
users who are tinkering a lot with this
type of setup where they get a VPS, a
virtual private server, essentially a
computer in the cloud, and install cloud
code into that. And so all of the files
and all of the context that their cloud
code builds with them lives in that
space. And so in that format, you get
the best of both worlds, right? Because
you get routines that don't die out and
actually run 24/7. and you're operating
through just one agentic platform which
is cloud code in this case but you can
also use codeex and you don't have to
use an external tool like sync thing in
order to sync files between your two
different setups. So it's highly
possible that openai and entropic will
offer something like this in the future
but obviously because of file storage
and security concerns that's probably
something that you can expect sometime
in the near future instead of now. Now,
let's go to the final element, which is
applications. Because if you're trying
to do any real work with your agents,
then you need to be able to connect to
your apps. And at the very first level,
the way that you connect to these
applications is probably through the
cloud code desktop app. Where from here,
if you go to customize and under the
connectors section here, you can find
and browse the different applications
that you can connect to. But in my view,
this is actually not the most efficient
way to connect to these applications
because if you go to the second level,
you can actually just have cloud code
connect to these applications itself or
search for what connectors exist instead
of you having to do it for cloud. At
least for me personally, what I use to
find connectors is this skill that I
have called search connectors. And what
it basically does is search the web for
the official connectors if there's any
or if there's none. Sometimes there's
communitymade connectors that are in the
form of CLIs or command line interfaces
or APIs or MCPs. So basically these are
the three usual formats that people use
to connect their AI agents to their
applications. To give an example, I use
search connectors for Adobe Premiere
here and look to check if there's an
official one from Adobe. It also look
for anything community made and by the
end of it, it provides a recommendation
which right now is this open-source repo
which is available on GitHub. And so if
I want to use this connector, then I'll
just continue this session and ask
Claude code to scan it if it's safe and
to set it up so that we can start using
it. But the great thing about these AI
agents is that if you take it to the
next level, what you can actually do is
to build your own connectors and to
build your own applications. Now,
there's many ways to build your own
connectors, but the one that I use
personally is the CLI printing press
from Matt VH, who is the co-founder of
Lyft. And I actually made a separate
video on this if you want to check it
out. But essentially what you can do
with this is to create connectors for
applications that don't have them. So in
this video I created one for my fitness
pal as well as for school because no
agentic connector really exists for
those platforms. And of course nothing
stops you from creating your own
applications as well. Like for instance
this whole dashboard is one type of
application but apart from that you can
see I also built out these micro apps
that I use almost on the daily. I have
this app where all of the generations
for images and videos that you see on
this channel and in our business
actually end up in this masonry grid so
that it's much easier to preview. I of
course have that second brain system
which I've shown already quite a lot.
And those excal illustrations that
you're seeing, I actually have Claude
build out this landing pad where I can
just copy in those artifacts that it
creates for me and just use them
depending on the visual that I'm trying
to communicate. And so whenever it makes
sense, I encourage you to try out
creating your own applications yourself
because then you will realize just how
powerful these agentic platforms can be.
So there that is the ARMS framework in
full. And I hope that was useful for you
to craft your own perfect agentic
operating system. And if you want the
full guide along with all of the prompts
that I shared here so that you can start
creating something like this for
yourself or for a client as well, then
feel free to just grab this PDF and send
it to your cloud code which you can find
down in the description. That's it for
this one. Thanks for watching till the
end as usual and I'll see you all next
time. Thanks.